waitrose.com 2016-06-09

# Privacy policy

**In summary**

Below, we tell you in detail how we use and store all of your personal and web-use data but, in summary, any personal information you give us is safe and confidential: we store all of your information on a secure server and never share any of your personal details with anybody outside of the John Lewis Partnership for their mailing or marketing purposes.

**Your personal details**

Your privacy is of the highest importance to us, and we promise never to release your personal details to any outside company for their mailing or marketing purposes (although we reserve the right to disclose this information in the circumstances set out below). We treat all of your personal information as confidential and keep it on a secure server.

**When we may use your personal details**

To provide you with the best possible service, we’d like to keep you up-to-date with a range of products and services provided by the John Lewis Partnership including John Lewis, Waitrose and John Lewis Financial Services. This may include news of special events, promotions, product launches and catalogues. As we are constantly looking to improve our services, we may occasionally contact you for research purposes by post, telephone, SMS text messaging and / or email. You can choose not to receive further information from us by clicking the relevant boxes during registration.

You have the right to request a copy of any information about you we hold at any time, and also to have that information corrected if it is inaccurate. To view any information you have disclosed, contact The Company Secretary, John Lewis Partnership, 171 Victoria Street, London SW1E 5NN. Nothing in these Terms and Conditions affects your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998.

**Using this website and your personal details**

You do not have to provide any information to us to use this website. However, certain sections of the site or facilities within the site may not be accessible if you choose not to share essential information with us.

When you shop on Waitrose.com we will ask you to submit – and will collect – personal information from you, including: your name, email address, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, product selections, credit card / other payment information, and a password. We, and our third-party advertisement and content providers, may collect information about your internet connection and website-use, e.g. the URL you came from, IP address, domain type, browser type, the country and telephone code where your computer is located, the web pages viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms you entered on our website (User Information). We may collect this information from registered and unregistered users. We use this information to help us make improvements to our website and online services.

Any personal information you provide to us (or which is available on public registers) and any User Information from which we identify you is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Information Commissioner’s Office. We use your information for the following purposes only:

  * To process your order
  * For statistical purposes to improve this website and the services we offer
  * To provide you with relevant content and advertisements
  * To administer this website

If you have chosen during registration to receive notification of products or special offers that may be of interest to you, then we may use your personal information to send you these notifications by telephone, email or in writing.

Your personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within the John Lewis Partnership and to reputable third-parties who will help process your order. The John Lewis Partnership requires all such third-parties to treat your personal information as confidential and to comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation in place at any given time.

We may disclose your personal information and / or User Information if we are asked to do so by the police or any other regulatory or Government authority investigating suspected illegal activities.

**How we collect User Information using cookies**

On Waitrose.com, cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor the website to your needs. Cookies help us to provide a more personalised online service to you and our cookies do not store any sensitive or confidential information. You can set your computer/mobile phone/other device to accept all cookies, notify you when a cookie is issued, or not receive cookies at any time. Please bear in mind that certain personalised features of this website cannot be provided to you without the use of cookies. Each browser is different so check the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences if you wish to do so.

A list of the main cookies that Waitrose.com sets, along with details of what each one is used for can be found on the Waitrose Cookies page.

### More information about cookies and how Waitrose.com uses them

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your device’s browser from a website’s computer and is stored on your device’s hard drive. Cookies allow a website to recognise a user’s device. Websites can send their own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it.

For more information see [www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

**How does Waitrose.com use cookies?**

During any visit to Waitrose.com, the pages you view – along with a cookie – are downloaded to your device. This allows us to store information to operate the site as you move from page to page.

Waitrose.com uses cookies to help us analyse the profile of our visitors and provide them with a better, more personalised service. Cookies also allow us to provide our service to you - for instance, by retrieving your current shopping basket so that you can make purchases, by recognising you when you access the website and by making it easier for you to navigate our website.

Our cookies do not store financial information, or information which is capable of directly identifying you (such as your name or address). Cookies simply allow our website to retrieve this information from our systems in order to personalise and improve your experience of our website.

Because we rely on cookies in this way to personalise and improve your experience on our website, your browser needs to be set to accept cookies before you can place an order on Waitrose.com. Each browser is different so check the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences if you wish to do so.

**Third-party cookies on Waitrose.com**

When you are on Waitrose.com. you may notice that there is content from other websites - for example a video from YouTube - which we add from time to time to improve the user experience. As a result, you may be sent cookies from these other websites. Waitrose.com does not control these cookies and we suggest you check these third-party websites for more information about the cookies they use and how you can manage them.

**What cookies does Waitrose.com use and can I reject them?**

A list of the main cookies that Waitrose.com sets, along with details of what each one is used for can be found on the Website Cookies page.

You can set your browser to reject cookies (see the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to find out how to do this), but please bear in mind that if you do this, certain personalised features of this website cannot be provided to you.
